奕尚电影吧
我说简单一点 从知道的真相开始
Start simple. Start with what you know is the truth.
我叫做凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩 我的故乡在12区
My name is Katniss Everdeen. My home is District 12.
我参加了饥饿游戏 我逃了出来
I was in the Hunger Games. I escaped.
皮塔 皮塔被落下了
Peeta... Peeta was left behind.
伊夫狄恩小姐 你不能待在这儿
Miss Everdeen? You can't be here.
我刚刚做了噩梦 就给我五分钟
I had a nightmare. Just five more minutes.
你得去睡会儿 我们能帮助你入睡
You need to sleep. We can help you sleep.
只要五分钟就行
Just five more minutes.
不
No.
不 请别这样 就五分钟
No, please, don't. It's just five more...
别碰我 不 不 不 放开我
Don't touch me! Don't! No! No! Get off of me!
芬尼克
Finnick.
I wanted to go back for Peeta and Johanna,
但是我
but I, uh...
我动不了
I couldn't move.
他们抓住了安妮 带走了她
They have Annie, too. They took her.
她
She's, uh...
在凯匹特
She's in the Capitol.
我希望她已经死了
I wish she was dead.
我希望他们都死了 我们也都死了
I wish they were all dead and we were too
饥饿游戏
嘲笑鸟
上
伊夫狄恩小姐
Miss Everdeen.
我是博格斯上校 13区首席治安官
Colonel Boggs, District 13's head of security.
我知道你已被获准出院
I know you've been discharged,
但科恩总统想先见见你
but President Coin's requested to meet with you first.
有什么新消息吗
Is there any news?
我只是来护送你的
I'm just here to escort you.
我们一直以为13区什么都不剩了
We were always told there was nothing left of 13.
凯匹特把地表都夷为了平地
Capitol bombed the surface to rubble.
但我们是军人 所以学会了在地下生存
But we're military, so we learned to survive down here.
准备着 训练着
Preparing, training.
战争对我们来说永远不会结束
The war never stopped for us.
就是她
There she is.
燃烧的女孩
Our Girl on Fire.
总统女士 这位就是嘲笑鸟
Madam President, may I present you with The Mockingjay.
很荣幸能见到你
What an honor it is to meet you.
你是个勇敢的女孩
You're a courageous young woman.
我知道这一定很令人费解
I know how disorienting this must be.
而且我无法想象
And I can't imagine what it's like to
你是如何赢得这些残酷的比赛的
live through the atrocities of those Games.
凯特尼斯
Katniss,
这位是阿尔玛·科恩总统
President Alma Coin.
要知道你在这儿是很受欢迎的
Please know how welcome you are.
希望你把这儿当家一样
I hope you'll find some comfort with us.
我们已经知道我们13区的损失
We've known loss in 13, too.
这就是历史 发生在这张桌子上的事
This is history. Right here at this table.
非常抱歉
I apologize.
没能给你更多的时间去恢复
I wish you had more time to recover,
但是不幸的是 我们不能那么奢侈
but unfortunately, we don't have that luxury.
请入座
Please, have a seat.
你知道发生了什么吗
Are you aware of what's happened?
当你在赛场上射出那一箭的时候
When you fired your arrow at the force field
全国人民为之沸腾
you electrified the nation.
有七个区发生了暴动
There have been riots and uprisings
起义和罢工
and strikes in seven districts.
我们坚信 如果我们想抗击凯匹特
We believe that if we keep this energy going
就必须把这样的精神延续下去
we can unify the districts against the Capitol.
但如果不这样 如果我们任凭它消逝
But if we don't, if we let it dissipate,
那么要过75年才会再有这样的机会
we could be waiting another 75 years for this opportunity.
13区的所有人都已经做好了战斗准备
Everyone in 13 is ready for this.
皮塔呢 皮塔还活着吗
What about Peeta? Is he alive?
不知道 但我希望能尽快找到他
I don't know. And I wish that I did.
但我暂时没法联系上
But there's no way for me to contact
我们打入凯匹特的内线
my operatives inside the Capitol.
凯匹特总是限制
The Capitol has always suppressed
区与区之间的通信
communication between the districts.
但我很了解他们的系统
But I know their system very well.
我可以绕过他们的防火墙
I managed to break through.
我们现在需要的是一条完美的讯息
All we need now is the perfect message.
凯特尼斯 这是我们必须做的
Katniss, here's what we need to do.
我们要向人们证明嘲笑鸟活得好好的
We need to show them that The Mockingjay's alive and well
并且愿意站出来 加入到这场战争中
and willing to stand up and join this fight.
因为我们希望每个区
'Cause we need every district
都能起义反抗凯匹特
to stand up to this Capitol.
就像你一样
The way you did.
所以 我们要拍一系列的宣传短片
So we're gonna shoot a series of propaganda clips,
我喜欢称之为
propos, I like to call them,
嘲笑鸟行动
on The Mockingjay.
广泛散播
Spreads the word
我们将要燃起这场起义之火的消息
that we're gonna stoke the fire of this rebellion.
一场由嘲笑鸟点燃的火
The fire that The Mockingjay started.
你把皮塔扔下了
You left him there.
你把皮塔扔在那里等死
You left Peeta in that arena to die.
凯特尼斯 我们也有难处
Katniss, there are so many...
皮塔才是应该活下来的那个人
Peeta was the one who was supposed to live.
伊夫狄恩小姐
Miss Everdeen.
这场革命事关所有人
This revolution is about everyone.
事关我们每一个人
It's about all of us.
我们需要一个声音
And we need a voice.
那你就应该救了皮塔
Then you should've saved Peeta.
也许你真该先救那个男孩出来
Maybe you should have rescued the boy instead.
不
Oh, no.
不 听我说 这事只能让她来做
No, listen to me. No one else can do this but her.
这可不是你所描述的那个女孩
This is not the girl you described.
很显然 我们应该换种方式
Obviously, we need to make it personal.
提醒她真正的敌人是谁
Remind her who the real enemy is.
她知道谁是她的敌人 这不是关键问题
She knows who the enemy is. That's not the issue.
除非她忘了伤痛
Unless she's forgotten.
通过解释和展示
There's explaining and there's showing.
让她看清凯匹特对12区都做了哪些不齿之事
Let her see what the Capitol did to 12.
她是承受不住的 游戏已经把她毁了
She can't handle it. The Games destroyed her.
这是你唯一的选择
This is the only choice you have.
不是每个人都能如你所愿
People don't always show up
招之即来 挥之即去的 总统女士
the way you want them to, Madam President.
但是这种由愤怒激起的起义
But that anger, that anger-driven defiance,
才是我们想要的 我们可以为他们指明方向
that's what we want. And we can redirect it.
我们必须将所有区的人都团结起来
We need to unite these people out there
而不是让他们在游戏里
that have been doing nothing but killing each other
自相残杀那么多年
in an arena for years.
我们需要一个导火索
We have to have a lightning rod.
他们会追随她的 她就是这场革命的领军人物
They'll follow her. She's the face of the revolution.
让她意识到这点 让她回家看看
Let her see it. Let her go home.
送她回去吧
Send her.
我真不敢相信你要这么做
I can't believe you're going through with this.
你本可以拒绝的
You can say "No."
我要亲自去看看
I need to see it for myself.
这边走
This way.
13区完全控制了这一带
13 swept everything, top to bottom
所以你是安全的
so you'd be safe.
你确定不想让我跟你一起去
You sure you don't want me to go with you?
是的 我确定
Yeah. I'm sure.
我们在上面帮你盯着
We'll have our eyes on you from above.
原来是你啊
Figures.
嘿
Hey!
过来
Come on.
你难道不想见见波丽姆吗
Don't you wanna see Prim?
这就对了 你真是伤透了我的心
There you go. You're breakin' my heart.
嘘
Shh.
埃杰里亚
Egeria!
我们得把这几句话改一下
We need to fix these lines.
我不想叫他们起义军
I won't say "Rebels."
这些只是无谓的反抗
These are senseless acts of defiance.
我才不会如此高抬他们
And I won't legitimize them.
那我们就叫他们罪犯
We'll call them "Criminals."
一般
Mmm.
激进分子
"Radicals."
可以
Hmm.
不然我就得打破我的老规矩了
Otherwise we're breaking my oldest rule.
绝不能让你的敌人看见你在流血
Never let them see you bleed.
公民们
Citizens,
今晚我宣布 帕纳姆国统一了
tonight I address all of Panem as one.
黑暗的日子已经过去
Since the Dark Days,
一个属于帕纳姆国前所未有的和平年代已经到来
Panem has had an unprecedented era of peace.
这是建立在合作之上的和平
It is a peace built upon cooperation.
倡导法律和秩序
And a respect for law and order.
在过去的几周 你们有所耳闻的几起暴力事件
In the past weeks, you have heard of sporadic violence
是世纪极限赛的一些激进分子的个人行为
following the actions of a few radicals in the Quarter Quell.
选择这条毁灭之路的人
Those who choose this destructive path,
是因为他们不了解
your actions are based on a misunderstanding
我们是如何一起生存下来的
of how we have survived. Together.
这是一个合约
It is a contract.
每个区都要给凯匹特缴纳贡品 就像血液流向心脏
Each district supplies the Capitol. Like blood to a heart.
作为回报 凯匹特会保证每个区的秩序和安全
In return, the Capitol provides order and security.
集体罢工行为
To refuse work
会让这套完整的系统陷入危机
is to put the entire system in danger.
凯匹特是帕纳姆国的心脏
The Capitol is the beating heart of Panem.
没有心脏 谁都活不了
Nothing can survive without a heart.
跪在你们前面这些罪犯
The criminals that kneel before you
用某些象征性的标识来煽动起义
use symbols for the purpose of sedition.
因此 所有和嘲笑鸟
Which is why all images
有关的标识
of The Mockingjay
现均予以禁止使用
are now forbidden.
拥有这些标识将视为叛国
Possessing them will be considered treason.
并处以死刑
Punishable by death.
正义必须马上得到伸张
Justice shall be served swiftly.
秩序必须得到恢复
Order shall be restored.
那些忽视历史教训的人
To those who ignore the warnings of history,
即将付出最终的代价
prepare to pay the ultimate price.
没事了
It's okay.
我们都很好
We're okay.
我们都在这了
We're all here now.
毛莨花
Buttercup!
我偷偷把它带进来的
I smuggled him in.
还有爸爸的照片
I got Dad.
我还从厨房里拿了点药草回来
And I got some of your herbs from the kitchen.
他们有严格的规定
They have strict rules.
我不知道如果他们发现我们养猫 会怎么样
I don't know what they'll do if they find him here.
你得吃点东西
You should try to eat something.
凯匹特直播间
晚上好 各位观众
Hello. Good evening.
欢迎各位收看帕纳姆直播间
And a big welcome to all in Panem.
我是凯撒·弗里克曼
I'm Caesar Flickerman.
无论你是谁 无论你在做什么
And whoever you are, whatever it is you're doing,
如果你在忙 那请放下手头的工作
if you're working, put down your work.
如果你在吃 请放下你的刀叉
If you're having dinner, stop having dinner.
因为你们将会迫切地想见证今晚要发生的事
Because you are going to want to witness this tonight.
现在关于世纪极限赛那天发生的事
There has been rampant speculation
是流言满天飞
about what really happened in the Quarter Quell.
为了揭开这件事的面纱
And here to shed a little light
我们有幸请到了一位神秘嘉宾
on the subject for us is a very special guest.
有请皮塔·麦拉克先生
Please welcome Mr. Peeta Mellark.
皮塔 很多人都在好奇
Peeta, a lot of people
那天是怎么回事
feel as though they are in the dark.
是的 我知道他们的感受
Yeah, I know how they feel.
好了 给大家解释一下吧
Now, so set the stage for us.
告诉我们 那充满争议的一晚
Talk us through what really happened
到底发生了什么
on that final and controversial night.
首先 你必须知道
Well, first off, you have to understand
当你身处游戏之中
that when you're in the Games
你只有一个愿望 而且代价很高
you only get one wish. It's very costly.
你还活着
You're alive.
会让你付出生命作为代价
It costs your life.
我认为比生命的代价还要高
I think it costs more than your life.
什么意思 什么能比生命的代价还高
How do you mean? What's more than your life?
我的意思是杀掉无辜的人
I mean to murder innocent people,
这会毁了你的良知
that costs everything that you are.
没错
Yes.
所以你就抱着这样一个愿望活着
So you hold on to that one wish.
而那天晚上我的愿望就是 救凯特尼斯
And that night my wish was to save Katniss.
是的
Yes.
那天我应该和她一起逃跑的
I should've just run off with her
就像她希望的那样
earlier in the day like she'd wanted.
但是你并没有
But you didn't.
为什么 是因为你被比特的计划耽搁了吗
Why? Were you caught up in Beetee's plan?
不 我在忙着结盟
No, I was caught up trying to play allies.
然后他们把我们分开了
And then they separated us
我就在那时失去了她
and that's when I lost her.
然后电闪雷鸣
And then the lightning hit
整片竞技场被炸成了废墟
and the whole force field around the arena just blew out.
没错 但是 皮塔
Yes, but, Peeta,
这一切都是凯特尼斯干的
Katniss is the one who blew it out.
不是的
No.
你看到了录像
You saw the footage.
不 她不知道自己在做什么
No, she didn't know what she was doing.
我们都不知道
Neither of us knew
有个更大的计划正在发生 我们都不知道
there was a bigger plan going on. We had no idea.
-你不知道吗 -不知道
-You had no idea?  -No.
好吧 皮塔 至少可以说有很多人
All right. Well, Peeta, there are many who find this suspicious
都觉得有疑点 -是的
to say the least. Mmm-hmm.
看来 她是起义计划的一部分
It seems as though she was part of a rebel plan.
你觉得她被乔安娜弄得半死
Do you think it was part of her plan
也是她计划的一部分吗
to be almost killed by Johanna?
或者被闪电打的半残也是她计划的一部分
Or part of the plan to be paralyzed by lightning?
不 我们根本不是任何起义计划的一部分
No, we were not part of any rebel plan.
我们根本就不知道发生了什么事
We had no idea what was going on.
好的 我相信你 皮塔·麦拉克 谢谢
All right. I believe you, Peeta Mellark. Thank you.
不客气
Yeah.
我本想让你继续说说叛乱的事
And I was going to ask you to speak about the unrest
但我认为你现在情绪太激动了
but I think you might be too upset.
不 我没事
No, I can.
-你确定吗 -是的 当然
Are you sure? Yeah, absolutely.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望正在收看的各位不要再这样下去了
I want everyone who's watching to stop
不要再去想一场内战意味着什么
and to think about what a civil war could mean.
我们曾因此差点灭绝
We almost went extinct once before.
而现在我们的人民已经越来越少了
And now our numbers are even fewer.
他是他们的人
He's one of them.
这真的是我们想做的吗
Is this really what we wanna do?
他是个叛徒
He's a traitor.
自相残杀吗
Kill ourselves off?
杀戮解决不了任何问题
Killing is not the answer.
真不敢相信他竟然这样做
I can't believe he's doing this.
我们要立刻把武器都放下
Everyone needs to lay down their weapons immediately.
叛徒
Traitor!
他不是我们的一员
He's not one of us!
这是叛国
This is treason!
你在呼吁大家停火
Are you calling for a ceasefire?
是的 没错
Yeah. I am.
你就是个傀儡
You're a puppet!
吊死他
Hang him!
我希望大家停下
I want everyone to stop
这场无谓的暴乱
the senseless violence.
这不是正确的改革之路
This is not the path to change.
叛徒
Traitor!
这也不是正义之路
It's not the path to justice.
绝不可能停火
There can't be a ceasefire.
尤其是在斯诺做了这一切之后
Not after everything Snow's done.
他今晚本可以做出更大规模的负面影响
He could have done a lot of damage tonight.
大部分地区都本就没有参加这次革命的勇气
Most districts, people are still too afraid to join.
他们需要勇气
They need the courage.
你觉得他为什么会那么说
Why do you think he said that?
我不知道 也许他是被逼的
I don't know. Maybe he was forced.
他看起来没那么糟
He didn't look that bad.
或许他是为了保护你才不得不这样
Maybe he made some kind of deal to protect you.
他还身处游戏之中
He's still playing the game.
不 不 不
No! No! No!
对不起 我刚刚做了个噩梦
I'm sorry. It's just a nightmare.
没事的 我也经常做
That's okay. I get 'em, too.
皮塔
Peeta,
你能留下来陪我吗
will you stay with me?
好啊
Yeah.
永远
Always.
嘿
Hey.
睡不着吗
Can't sleep?
告诉我发生了什么事
Tell me what's happening.
我很擅长替别人保守秘密
I'm good at keeping secrets.
我不会和妈妈说的
Even from Mom.
没人比我更恨凯匹特了
No one hates the Capitol more than me.
我很想出一份力 但是我一直在想
And I wanna help. But I just keep thinking,
即使我们赢了这场战争 皮塔会怎么样
even if we win this war, what happens to Peeta?
我知道他在那边不安全
I know he's not safe there,
但他在这儿更不安全
but he's definitely not safe here.
我想你不知道
I don't think you know
你对他们来说有多重要
how important you are to them.
如果你想要什么 尽管和他们提
If you want something, you just have to ask.
你可以要任何你想要的东西
You could demand almost anything.
他们必须同意
They'd have to agree to it.
我真应该在晚上多叫醒你几次 小鸭子
I should wake you up more often, Little Duck.
好啦 快睡吧
Get some sleep now.
你也是
You, too.
谢谢你们百忙里抽出时间来见我
Thank you for agreeing to meet with me.
我决定加入嘲笑鸟行动
I've decided I'll be your Mockingjay.
但我有几个条件
But I have some conditions.
皮塔和其他的贡品
Peeta and the other Tributes,
乔安娜·梅森和安妮·克里斯塔
Johanna Mason and Annie Cresta,
要在第一时间营救
will be rescued at the earliest opportunity.
一旦皮塔被释放
If and when Peeta is liberated,
他将获得无条件豁免权
he will receive a full and unconditional pardon.
他将不受到任何惩罚
No punishment will be inflicted.
其他贡品也一样
And the same goes for the other Tributes.
不可能
No.
你们把他们丢在那里又不是他们的错
It's not their fault you abandoned them in the arena.
他们做的和说的一切都是为了生存
They're doing and saying whatever they can to survive.
在13区不接受有个人请求
Individuals don't make demands in 13.
会有法庭来做出公正的审判的
There will be a tribunal. And a fair judgment.
谢谢
Thank you.
胜利者享有豁免权
The Victors will be granted immunity.
你必须在
And you will announce that
13区所有人面前宣布
in front of the entire population of 13.
你和你的政府会履行这一职责
You will hold yourself and your government responsible
不然你们只能再去找一只嘲笑鸟了
or you will find another Mockingjay.
就是这样 这才像话
That's it. That's her. Right there.
这不就是我跟你保证过的吗
Isn't that who I promised you?
让她穿上制服
She wears the costume.
用战场作为背景 再来点烟雾
Gunfire in the background. A hint of smoke.
这就是我们的嘲笑鸟
Our Mockingjay.
总统女士 我们失去了家园
Madam President, we're losing ground,
就是因为人们失去了信心
because the people are losing heart.
我们值得为此冒险
This is worth the risk.
她值得我们冒险
She's worth the risk.
赦免也好 法院裁决也好 都依靠人民的力量
Pardons, tribunals. Power of the people.
这将会是新帕纳姆国的基石
It can all be the bedrock of the new Panem, but,
但是 在战争时刻 我认为即使是再高尚的目标
in wartime I think even the noblest of causes
也是可以通融一点的 对吧
can be bent a little bit. Right?
你还有其他要求吗
Do you have any other conditions?
我的妹妹可以留下她的猫
My sister gets to keep her cat.
走开
Go away.
又到了探访的时间吗
Is it visiting hours again?
特琳奇女士
Miss Trinket,
你看见这扇门了
you see this door.
它是可以从里面打开的
It opens. From the inside.
我告诉过你的 这里是
I've told you, these are the standard
标准的生活区 所有人都一样
living quarters. Same as everyone.
你不是什么犯人 你可以在13区自由活动
You're not a prisoner. You're free to join the rest of 13.
我这样怎么见人 谢谢啊
Not looking like this. Thank you very much.
我们的问题可比漂亮的衣服重要多了 特琳奇女士
We have a bigger issue than wardrobe, Miss Trinket.
凯特尼斯已经同意做我们的嘲笑鸟了
Katniss has agreed to be The Mockingjay.
可怜的孩子
That poor thing.
你的燃烧女孩已经过了黄金时代了
And your Girl on Fire is burnt out.
我希望你能加入我们
I need you to join this team now.
我需要一些她信得过的人
I need someone she trusts.
为什么不去找黑密曲
What about Haymitch?
他还在地下几层的地方戒酒呢
He's drying out in some facility a mile down.
协助叛乱真的不是我的专长
Aiding rebels is not really my forte.
特琳奇女士 无论这里发生什么事
Miss Trinket, your days in the Capitol are over,
你在凯匹特的那些日子已经结束了
no matter what happens here.
如果你想以战犯的身份待在这儿 那好吧
If you wanna play a prisoner of war, fine.
你就烂在这儿吧
Stay here and rot.
我去找别人来当嘲笑鸟的陪伴
I'll find someone else to be The Mockingjay's escort.
你打算去找谁
Who?
没有谁是不可替代的
Anyone can be replaced.
除了你的嘲笑鸟
Not your Mockingjay.
在这个暗无天日的地牢里
There isn't a soul in this dungeon
没有人比我更了解凯特尼斯了
who knows the first thing about Katniss.
你真的以为你们这些穴居人
You honestly believe one of these cave dwellers
能取代我的位置
is going to take my place?
不可能
No.
下午好
Good afternoon.
很抱歉打断了各位的的日程安排
Thank you for interrupting your schedules.
我们已针对这次延误进行了补偿调整
They have already been adjusted to compensate for the delay.
我怎么没看见有小孩子
I hardly ever see children around here.
请在恢复工作时和你们的车间负责人确认
Please, check in with your unit supervisors when you resume work.
几年前一场瘟疫夺走了不少人的性命
A lot of them were lost in an epidemic a few years ago.
我对13区的公民们有一份声明要宣布
I have an announcement for the citizens of 13.
科因总统也因此失去了她的家人
Coin lost her family, too.
她的女儿和丈夫
Daughter and a husband.
来自12区的客人
And our welcome guests from 12.
凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩已经
Katniss Everdeen has consented
同意作为我们的领军人物
to be the face of our cause
来帮助团结各区的人们共同对抗凯匹特
to help unite the districts against the Capitol.
作为回报 我承诺
In exchange, I have promised
做出一些让步
several concessions.
首先 我们会
First, we'll assess all opportunities
不遗余力地救出
for the extraction of the Victors
被关在凯匹特的胜利者
held hostage in the Capitol.
皮塔·麦拉克
Peeta Mellark,
乔安娜·梅森
Johanna Mason...
芬尼克 我也为救安妮和他们达成了协议
Finnick, I made the deal for Annie, too.
还有安妮·克里斯塔
...and Annie Cresta.
一旦他们获救
Once freed,
将赦免他们背叛起义军的
they will be granted full pardon for any and all crimes
所有罪行
committed against the rebel cause.
干得漂亮
Good.
真的 凯特尼斯
That's good, Katniss.
如果凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩不履行她的职责
If Katniss Everdeen fails to fulfill her duties
则该协议作废
the deal will be off.
谢谢大家
Thank you for your attention.
请回到各自的工作岗位上去吧
Please, resume your daily schedules.
总统女士
Madam President.
艾菲·特琳奇
Effie Trinket.
欢迎来到13区
Welcome to 13.
总统女士 我不得不说你的演讲真的
Madam President, may I say you are so very
-言简意赅 -嗯
- concise. - Mmm.
你觉得有必要说得更多吗
You believe that there's more to be said?
我能说直白一点吗
May I speak freely?
你似乎除了这个也不会其他的了
You don't appear to do anything else.
我只想说说推广艺术
I'm only talking about salesmanship.
革命就像一个小火苗
The thing with revolutions, they're a tender flame.
给点阳光
They need to be nurtured with a little kindling
才能灿烂
and warmth.
再来点氧气
Bit of oxygen.
氧气
Oxygen.
扑灭它的方法就是抽光氧气
One sure way to put it out is to smother it.
或者用尽房间里的所有空气
Or to use up all the air in the room.
失陪了
Excuse me.
你知道什么最用得上变革吗 她的发型
You know what could use a revolution? That hair.
艾菲
Effie?
哦
Oh!
你怎么在这儿
What are you doing here?
来这儿政治避难
I'm a political refugee.
普鲁塔什救了你
Plutarch rescued you?
救我 算是吧 他是这样说的
Rescued, yes, that's what he calls it.
我和你一样云里雾里的
You and I were both in the dark.
现在却要一辈子都穿着这身衣服了
Now I'm condemned to this life of jumpsuits.
很高兴再次见到你
It is wonderful to see you again.
这地方太难以置信了
Can you believe this place?
真怀念咖啡
I miss coffee.
我从来没想过这地方这么严格
I never knew anyplace could be so strict.
我是说 我以为至少
I mean, I thought at least
官阶高一点 就能享受一些
in the higher ranks there'd be some
特殊待遇
side action.
我怀念我的假发
I miss my wigs.
还好 我记得当我来这儿的时候
Luckily, I remembered that this was all the rage
这种打扮还是很时尚的
when I was coming up.
你知道的 时尚就是在不停的轮回
You know, everything old can be made new again.
就像民主
Like democracy.
让我想起了这个
Which brings me to this.
西纳
Cinna.
他死了 是吗
He's dead, isn't he?
是的 亲爱的
Yes, dear.
他让普鲁塔什答应他
He made Plutarch promise not to show you this
直到你自愿成为嘲笑鸟 再给你看这些设计
until you'd decided to be The Mockingjay on your own.
他知道其中的风险 我们都知道
He knew the risks. As we all do.
他相信这场变革
He believed in this revolution.
我仍然赌你赢
西纳
他相信你
He believed in you.
这些设计美极了
They're beautiful.
他们已经做出来了
They have it.
他们做出了嘲笑鸟的服装
They have the Mockingjay outfit.
在13区没有庞大的筹备组
There's not much of a prep team here in 13
但我们会让你
but we will make you
成为最佳着装的起义者
the best-dressed rebel in history.
好了
Okay.
开灯
Bring up the lights.
西纳的点睛之笔
Cinna's final touch.
所有人要么想亲你一口 要么想杀了你
Everyone's either gonna wanna kiss you, kill you,
要么想成为你
or be you.
完美了
Perfect.
相当完美
Absolutely perfect.
好了 把背景调出来
Okay. Let's bring up the setting.
嗯
Huh.
来点儿风
Little wind.
好的 凯特尼斯
Okay, Katniss,
我们从你单膝跪地开始
we're gonna start you down on one knee.
好的 然后你慢慢站起来
Okay. And as you rise up,
高举起你的旗帜 然后说台词
you're gonna hold your flag in the air and deliver your line.
还有要记住
And remember
你和你的兄弟姐妹们手挽手
you've just stormed the outskirts of the Capitol
攻到了凯匹特城的外围
arm-in-arm with your brothers and sisters.
好的
Okay.
准备好了就开始
Whenever you're ready.
帕纳姆的人民 我们战斗 我们勇猛 我们
People of Panem, we fight, we dare, we...
她知道台词吗
Does she know the line?
-我知道 我知道 抱歉 -好的 重新来
-I know it. I got it. I'm sorry. -Okay, All right.
-再来一遍  -她还在热身呢
-Let's do it again. -She's warming up.
好的 要有力量有感情 开始
All right. With energy. Go.
帕纳姆的人民 我们战斗
People of Panem, we fight!
我们要为正义 结束这饥饿的现状
We dare to end this hunger for justice!
记住你是在战斗中
You've just been in battle!
不好意思 我失态了
I'm sorry. Excuse my outburst.
记住你是在战斗中
You've just been in battle.
再试一次
Let's try it again.
准备好了就开始
Whenever you're ready.
帕纳姆的人民 我们战斗
People of Panem, we fight!
我们要为正义 结束这饥饿的现状
We dare to end this hunger for justice.
我的朋友们 我们的革命之火就这么熄灭了
And that, my friends, is how a revolution dies.
你好啊 凯特尼斯
Hello, Katniss.
你就这么跟老朋友打招呼吗
This how you greet an old friend?
你戒了酒我认不出来了
Maybe I don't recognize you sober.
大概我看起来和实际感觉一样糟透了
I guess it looks as bad as it feels.
帕纳姆的人民 我们战斗
People of Panem, we fight!
我们要为正义 结束这饥饿的现状
We dare! We end this hunger for justice!
呃 总统女士
Uh, Madam President,
请允许我废话几句
indulge me for a moment, if you would.
让我们来想想哪怕一点
Let's everybody think of one incident
凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩真正打动了你们的地方
where Katniss Everdeen genuinely moved you.
不是因为你们嫉妒她的发型的时候
Not where you were jealous of her hairstyle
或她的裙子着火的时候
or her dress went up in flames
又或者是她百步穿杨的时候
or she made a halfway decent shot with an arrow.
更不是皮塔让她变得更可爱的时候
And not where Peeta made you like her.
不 我希望你们想象那一瞬间
No, I'd like you all to think of one moment
她让你们有那一瞬间的实感 哦
where she made you feel something real. Oh.
她自愿替代她妹妹参赛的那个瞬间
When she volunteered for her sister at the Reaping.
好想法
Excellent example.
好了
Okay.
我希望我没把重要的东西抹掉
I hope that wasn't important.
呃 好吧 替代妹妹参赛
Uh... Okay. "Volunteer for sister."
不错 还有吗
Good. What else?
哦 当她为小女孩鲁唱那首歌的时候
Oh. When she sang that song for little Rue.
哦 没错 无论谁都被感动的哽咽了
Oh, yeah. Who didn't get choked up at that?
你知道吗 艾菲 我还是喜欢没化妆的你
You know, I like you better, Effie, without all that makeup.
我倒是喜欢没喝醉的你
Well, I like you better sober.
当她选择鲁为盟友的时候
When she chose Rue as an ally, as well.
嗯 没错
Mmm, yes.
那么 这些事有什么共同点吗
Now, what do all these have in common?
没人告诉她怎么做
No one told her what to do.
未经编排的 没错
Unscripted, yes.
所以 或许我们应该让她一个人静一静
So maybe we should just leave her alone.
把她的妆洗掉
And wash her face.
她还是个女孩 化了妆像孩儿他妈一样
She's still a girl. You made her look 35.
显然在地下生活久了
The opportunities for spontaneity
缺乏这种自主的机会
are obviously lacking below ground.
所以你建议把她扔到战场上
So what you're suggesting is we toss her into combat?
我绝对不允许 为了达到拍摄效果
I can't sanction putting an untrained civilian
就把一个未经训练的平民放在战场上
in battle just for effect.
这里不是凯匹特
This is not the Capitol.
这正是我的建议 让她身处实战之中
That is exactly what I'm suggesting. Put her in the field.
不 我们没法保护她
No, we can't protect her.
一切都要发自她内心
It has to come from her.
这样人们才会有共鸣
That's what people respond to.
你们想要这场革命的标志
You want a symbol for the revolution?
那就别教她怎么做 相信我 我懂
She cannot be coached into it. Trust me, I know.
也许有一个地方不是那么危险
Maybe there's someplace that's less dangerous.
第8区 报道说那里上星期刚被轰炸过
District 8. They reported heavy bombing last week.
那里已经没有任何军事目标了
There are no military targets left.
我们无法保证她的安全
We can't guarantee her safety.
你永远无法保证我的安全
You'll never be able to guarantee my safety.
我要去
I wanna go.
如果你被杀了怎么办
And if you're killed?
那就确保你拍下了整个过程
Make sure you get it on camera.
我为你准备了点惊喜
I've made you some surprises.
不想试试吗
Maybe you wanna try one out.
如果你要成为凯特尼斯的拍摄小分队成员
If you're gonna be a part of Katniss' propo team,
你最好还是把功能都试一遍
you may as well look the part.
这把弓是给你的
And this one is for you.
普鲁塔什想为这次拍摄
Plutarch wanted you to have a weapon
为你打造一把专属武器
for the sake of the propos
但我不可能只为你做一个时尚配件
but I couldn't just make you a fashion accessory.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
再看看这儿
And look here.
普通的 可燃的 爆炸的箭
Regular. Incendiary. Explosive arrows.
用颜色区分
All color-coded.
告诉芬尼克
And tell Finnick
我为他做了把三叉戟
I've got a trident for him
他随时可以来拿
when he's ready.
也许这能让他振作起来吧
Might just cheer him... Cheer him up.
呃
Uh...
还是别在这儿试这红色的箭吧
Let's not fire the red ones in here.
你们拥有这么多武器
You had all of this and you just
却让各区自生自灭
left the districts to fend for themselves?
没那么简单的 凯特尼斯 我们也是苟延残喘
It's not that simple, Katniss. We barely survived.
我们没有足够的能力
We weren't in any kind of shape
发动反击
to launch a counterattack.
是啊 我们是能炸了凯匹特
Yeah, we could've bombed the Capitol
但是他们能以至少两倍的火力
but they would've retaliated
向我们报复
with at least twice the firepower.
然后呢
Then what?
连个享受胜利的人都没有
There would've been nobody left to claim victory.
听起来就像皮塔说的一样
Sounds like exactly what Peeta said
但你们却称他为叛徒
and then you all called him a traitor.
这边走 战士
This way, soldier.
你已经准备好上镜了
You are camera-ready.
你的战友是不是看起来很帅
Doesn't your comrade look handsome?
出发吧
Let's go.
平安归来
Come back safe.
我来简单介绍一下 凯特尼斯
Quick introductions, Katniss.
这几位都是远道而来支持起义的
These people have come a long way to support the cause.
这位是克雷西达
This is Cressida.
在我看来 她是凯匹特
In my opinion one of the best
最有前途的导演
up-and-coming directors in the Capitol.
直到我离开 嘿
Until I up and left. Hey.
嘿
Hey.
让我们拭目以待吧
Let's see what you can do.
好了 万事小心
All right. Be careful.
这位是我的助手 莫撒拉
This is my assistant, Messalla.
很荣幸见到你
It's an honor to meet you.
那位是你的专属摄影师 凯斯特
And your cameramen over there, Castor.
你好
Hello.
还有波力克斯
And Pollux.
关上舱门准备起飞了
Let's get locked in.
你们都是从凯匹特来的吗
You're all from the Capitol?
普鲁塔什救的你们
Plutarch got you out?
别指望他能告诉你什么
Don't expect much chitchat from him.
他是个艾瓦克斯 凯匹特几年前就割了他的舌头
He's an Avox. Capitol cut his tongue out years ago.
如果你指的是营救
And, no, it wasn't any sort of rescue,
那么 不 我们不是
if that's what you mean.
我们是自己逃出来的
We all fled on our own.
为了起义
For this.
为了你
For you.
一定要快 速战速决
This has gotta be fast. In and out.
行动
Move out.
看来你还活着 我们一直不确定
You're alive then. We weren't sure.
凯特尼斯 这位是第8区的总指挥官 佩拉
Katniss, Commander Paylor, District 8.
凯特尼斯仍处于康复阶段 但她坚持要出来
Katniss has been recovering, but she insisted on coming out
来看看你们的伤员
and seein' some of your wounded.
我们最不缺的就是伤员了
Well, we've got plenty of those.
我们在西边几个街区外挖了公墓
We have a mass grave a few blocks west, but,
但还没腾出人手去搬运尸体
I can't spare the manpower to move them yet.
帘子后面就是医院
Hospital's past that curtain.
你能给予他们的任何希望 都是值得的
Any hope you can give them, it's worth it.
凯匹特用尽一切办法要将我们一网打尽
The Capitol's done everything they can to break us.
把伤病员都聚在一间屋子里合适吗
Aren't you worried about having all your wounded in one place?
至少比扔下他们不管要合适
I think it's better than leaving them to die.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
没办法 这是我目前唯一的选择
Well, that's my only other option.
如果你能说出什么好办法 那我洗耳恭听
You can come up with another, I'm all ears.
就在这儿
It's right through here.
别在这里拍 我帮不了他们什么
Don't film me in there. I can't help them.
让他们看见你就行
Just let them see your face.
行吗
Huh?
借过一下
Excuse me.
你没事吧
Yeah. You all right?
没事的 没事的
It's okay. Here, it's okay.
我在这儿 没事的
I've got you. It's all right.
凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩
Katniss Everdeen?
你在这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
我来看望你们
I came to see you.
那你的孩子呢
What about the baby?
孩子掉了
I lost it.
你会挺身而出吗 凯特尼斯
Are you fighting, Katniss?
你是来和我们并肩战斗的吗
You here to fight with us?
是的
I am.
没错
I will.
拉近
Tighter.
拉近 特写
Tighter, tighter.
总统先生 一些监控摄像头在轰炸时损坏了
Sir, some cameras were damaged in the bombings,
但我们能确认是她
but we confirmed it's her.
放大
Zoom in.
她在一家临时医院
She was visiting a makeshift hospital.
我们不确定她现在还在不在那里
We're not sure if she's still there.
嗯
Hmm.
我们可以从11区边境紧急调派轰炸机过来
We can scramble hovercraft from the border of 11.
或许我们能锁定她
We may be able to target her.
恩
Hmm.
把那些伤患杀了
Kill the wounded.
总统先生
Sir...
演讲稿是你写的 埃杰丽亚
You wrote that speech yourself, Egeria.
任何与嘲笑鸟标识相关的
Any association with the Mockingjay symbol
都是被禁止的
is forbidden.
那间医院里的所有人都犯了叛国罪
Everyone inside that hospital has committed treason.
告诉他们 和凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩
Show them what it costs
做朋友的后果有多严重
to be friends with Katniss Everdeen.
你的母亲看到这段录像会以你为豪的
Your mom's gonna be proud of you when she sees the footage.
录像会在各区播放吗
Will this play in the districts?
会牢牢地纹在他们眼睛上的
It'll be tattooed on their eyes.
有情况
There's a problem.
什么情况
What kinda problem?
有轰炸机从北边来了
Incoming bombers from the north.
我们得找地方避一避
We need to find cover now.
那边就有一个防空洞
There's a bunker in there.
就在正前方的台阶下
Straight ahead and down the stairs.
凯特尼斯
Katniss!
伊夫狄恩 伊夫狄恩
Everdeen! Everdeen!
盖尔 离墙远一点
Gale, back away from the wall!
你没事吧
You okay?
快跑
Move!
他们目标集中在南方某个地方
They're going after something to the south.
他们冲着医院去了
That's towards the hospital.
他们在上空盘旋 快来
They're circling back around. Come on!
是医院
That's the hospital.
他们在轰炸医院
They're targeting the hospital.
快去救他们
Help them!
快去救他们 把他们救出来
Help them! Get them out!
凯特尼斯
Katniss?
凯特尼斯 你能告诉大家
Katniss, can you tell everyone
你现在都看见了什么吗
what you're seeing right now?
凯特尼斯 你想说什么
Katniss, what do you wanna say?
我要让起义军知道我还活着
I want the rebels to know that I'm alive.
我就在第8区
That I'm in District 8
凯匹特刚刚轰炸了一间
where the Capitol just bombed a hospital
满是手无寸铁的男人 妇女和孩子的医院
filled with unarmed men, women and children.
没人能幸存
And there will be no survivors.
如果你哪怕有一丝期望
If you think for one second
认为凯匹特会公平的对待我们
that the Capitol will ever treat us fairly
那你就是在欺骗自己
you are lying to yourselves.
因为我们知道他们是哪种人
Because we know who they are
他们都做了哪些禽兽行径
and what they do.
这就是他们的所作所为 我们必须还以颜色
This is what they do! And we must fight back.
我要给斯诺总统带句话
I have a message for President Snow.
你可以折磨我们 轰炸我们
You can torture us and bomb us
把我们的家园夷为平地
and burn our districts to the ground.
但你们看到了吗
But do you see that?
熊熊火焰已经点燃
Fire is catching.
如果我们被点燃 你们必会一起葬身火海
And if we burn, you burn with us!
因为我们知道他们是哪种人
We know who they are and what they do.
这就是他们的所作所为
This is what they do!
我们必须还以颜色
And we must fight back.
你可以折磨我们 轰炸我们
You can torture us and bomb us
把我们的家园夷为平地
and burn our districts to the ground.
普鲁塔什没有看错你
Plutarch's faith in you wasn't misplaced.
但你们看到了吗
But do you see that?
谢谢
Thank you.
熊熊火焰正在燃烧
Fire is catching.
和我一起主持开场吧
Come up with me for the beginning.
如果我们被点燃 你们必会一起葬身火海
And if we burn, you burn with us!
加入嘲笑鸟
加入战斗
没有妥协就没有退却
There is no progress without compromise.
没有牺牲就没有胜利
No victory without sacrifice.
现在 我和我们的嘲笑鸟站在这里
But I stand here with The Mockingjay
一起宣布 我们的时代已经到来
to announce that our moment has arrived.
比特把我们的视频使用率
Beetee has increased
扩展了十倍
our use of the airwaves tenfold.
今晚我们将把这一消息
We will broadcast this message
广播到各个区
to all the districts tonight.
嘲笑鸟的话
The Mockingjay's words
激励着大家参与起义活动
inspiring everyone to join the rebellion.
携手作战
Together,
我们将是一个
we will become
不容小觑的联盟
an alliance to be reckoned with.
你不喜欢在葬礼上听见战曲 对吧
You don't like hearing a fight song at a funeral, huh?
越多的人加入我们
The more people on our side,
我们离解救皮塔和安妮就更进一步
the closer we are to Peeta and Annie.
没错
Yeah.
第七区
斯诺总统下令
By order of President Snow
日生产指标必须有所提高
daily production quotas have been increased.
所有工时将增加2小时
All work shifts will be extended by an extra two hours.
不容许产量不达标
Failure to meet these quotas will not be tolerated.
斯诺总统下令
By order of President Snow
日生产指标必须有所提高
daily production quotas have been increased.
如果我们被点燃 你们必会一起葬身火海
If we burn, you burn with us!

-我有一个好消息 -是什么
-I got good news. -What?
科因总统同意让我们在地上狩猎
Coin agreed to let us hunt above ground.
它一点都不怕我们
He's not even afraid of us.
那是因为它们从未被猎捕过
It's 'cause they've never been hunted before.
这一点也不公平
It's almost not fair.
他们要我们回去
They want us back.
他们让我们去指挥部
They asked us to head for Command.
好 我先把这些放下
All right. I gotta drop these off.
毫无异议
She was arguably
她是我们最喜欢的贡品
our favorite Tribute.
而让所有人都意想不到的是
And I think that's what we all find most astonishing,
这个女孩在凯匹特受到了崇拜
is that this girl was adored in the Capitol.
我想 对于你来说 皮塔
And I think for you, Peeta,
这一定让你非常心痛
it must be particularly painful.
我真希望能把这朵玫瑰花送给你 凯特尼斯
I wish I could give this rose to you, Katniss.
他这么快就变了这么多
He's changed so much already.
他们对他做了什么
What are they doing to him?
对一个激起这么多暴力事情的女孩
A sweet gesture for a girl who has inspired
做出如此甜蜜的举动
such violence.
你一定是很爱她 爱到足以原谅她
You must love her very much to be able to forgive her.
他在发抖
He's shaking.
我想我不能原谅他
I don't think that I could.
当然了 皮塔 除非你觉得她是
Unless, of course, Peeta, you think that perhaps she's being
被迫讲了那番
forced into saying
她自己都不理解的话
things that she doesn't even understand.
是的 我正是那么认为
Yeah. That's exactly what I think.
他连声音都变了
Even his voice is different.
我认为他们利用她
I think they're using her
来发动起义
to whip up the rebels.
我想她可能都不知道发生了什么事
I doubt she even knows what's happening.
不知道这事的利害攸关
And what's really at stake.
可现在 皮塔 我怀疑起义军
Now, Peeta, I doubt that the rebels
绝不会让她看到这段视频
will ever let her see this.
但如果他们让看的话 你想对她说什么
But if they do, what would you say to her?
对凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩
To Katniss Everdeen,
对曾经那么甜美的凯特尼斯·伊夫狄恩说些什么
the once sweet Katniss Everdeen.
我想告诉她 要替她自己想想
I would tell her to think for herself.
是的
Yes.
别那么傻 凯特尼斯
Don't be a fool, Katniss.
我知道你从不曾想要起义的
I know you never wanted the rebellion.
你在游戏里做的那些事
The things that you did in the Games
从来不是为了发动这一切的
were never intended to start all of this.
起义军经把你变得
The rebels have made you into something
不是你自己了
that you're not.
变成了能够毁灭我们的武器
Something that could destroy all of us.
所以 如果你对他们的行动
So if you have any power or any say
对他们如何利用你有说话权的话
in what they do or how they use you,
求你 求你了 要求他们停止这场战争吧
please, please, urge them to stop this war
现在还为时不晚
before it's too late.
问问你自己
And ask yourself,
你信任与你一同共事的那些人吗
can you trust the people you're working with?
你知道他们真正想要的是什么吗
Do you know what they really want?
我们必须做出回应
We need to respond.
谢谢你 皮塔·麦拉克 谢谢你
Thank you, Peeta Mellark, for these
对真正的嘲笑鸟的真情流露
revelations about the real Mockingjay.
你注意到他的神情了吗
Did you see what he looks like?
我看见了一个懦夫
I saw a coward.
你根本不知道他遭遇了什么
You don't have any idea what he's going through.
我不管 我永远不会说出他刚刚说的那些话
I don't care. I would never say what he just said.
就是他们折磨我 拿枪指着我的头 我也不会
Not if they tortured me. Not with a gun to my head.
是他保护你不受人鞭打
That is the same Peeta that defended you at the whipping post.
不 不是 现在他只是保护着他自己
No, it's not. Now he's only defending himself.
科因召集开会了 我们得反击
Coin's called a meeting. We need to respond.
你什么时候跟科因是一伙的了
When did "We" Become you and Coin?
每个人都有自己的选择
Everyone has a choice.
他怎么能够坐在凯匹特 替那些
How can he sit there in the Capitol and defend the people
毁了他的家园 杀害了他亲人的人辩护
who destroyed his home and murdered his family?
他什么都不知道
He doesn't know.
他怎会知道
How could he?
没人亲眼看到凯匹特对12区做了什么
Nobody's seen what the Capitol did to 12.
我们必须向他证明这一点
I have to show them.
我会和你在
So I wanna start with you
司法楼门口开拍 好吗
in front of the Justice Building, okay?
开始 第一拍
Bang. First shot.
凯特尼斯 告诉我们这里发生了什么
Katniss, tell us what happened here.
我们当时就站在这里
We were all standin' right here
看着你在游戏中射出那支箭
watchin' the Games when you fired that arrow.
屏幕突然黑了
The screens just went dark.
没人知道发生了什么
Nobody had any idea what happened.
治安警员把我们驱赶回家
Peacekeepers forced us back into our homes.
将近一小时左右 整个镇上一片死寂
For maybe an hour, the town was just dead quiet.
到了九点钟 我们听到治安卡车开走的声音
Little past 9:00, we heard their trucks pullin' out.
所有的治安警员都走了
All of them. Every single Peacekeeper.
我知道那意味着什么
And I knew what that meant.
我和几个矿工
Me and a couple of guys from the mines,
我们开始把拉着大家离开他们的房子
we started pulling people from their houses
试图他们带到警戒线外
and tried to get 'em to the fence line
但很多人害怕森林
but a lotta people were scared of the forest.
所以他们朝着公路去了
So they headed up onto the road.
趁人不注意往那边跑了
Make a break for it that way.
继续拍盖尔
Stay with Gale.
我们一共有915人逃到了警戒线外
915 of us made it to the fence.
之后我们亲眼看着轰炸机对着公路轰炸
Then we watched as bombers circled back towards the road.
他们对着逃跑的人扔炸弹
They firebombed them as they ran away.
一万人中我们只逃出了915人
915 outta 10,000.
当时我该拦下他们
I should've grabbed people.
我该拖住他们和我一起逃的
I should've dragged 'em with me.
我本可以带出更多孩子的
Some of the kids I could've carried.
你已经拯救了很多人了 盖尔
You saved so many people, Gale.
没有你 就没有12区
Without you, there would be no District 12.
甚至连回忆都不会留下
Not even the memory of it.
你在这儿吻的我
This is where you kissed me.
我没想到你还记得
I didn't think you remembered that.
除非我死了才会忘记
I'd have to be dead to forget that.
也许到死都忘不了
Maybe not even then.
我就知道你会这么做
I knew you'd do that.
为什么 我自己都不知道
How? I didn't.
因为我处于痛苦之中
'Cause I'm in pain.
只有这样我才能得到你的注意
That's the only way that I can get your attention.
别担心 凯特尼斯 一切都会过去的
Don't worry, Katniss. It'll pass.
嘿
Hey.
是的 是只嘲笑鸟
Yeah, that's a mockingjay.
这下它们静不下来了
Well, now they'll never shut up.
你想让我唱一曲
You want me to sing?
歌词原本是 绳索项链
That line was originally "Necklace of rope."
我把它改成了 希望项链
I had it changed to "Necklace of hope."
哇哦 你还真是个作家啊
Wow. You are a true wordsmith.
有点生硬 不过 当然 这方面技巧跟打仗一样好
Little on the nose, but, of course, so is war.
每个区都能看到这视频吗
Every district's seeing this?
是的 除了凯匹特
Yes. But not the Capitol.
我针对他们设计了这个信号防御系统
I designed this signal defense system for them.
我还没有找到能够破解的方法
But I can't find my way through it.
我想是我的工作做得太出色了
Guess I did my job too well.
那时候 我满脑子都是科学
At the time, I was just thinking of the science of it all.
我们会成功的
We'll get through it.
进攻 准备反击
Moves and countermoves.
凯特尼斯 你去趟指挥部
Katniss, you're wanted in Command.
今晚 我们收到了
Tonight, we've received reports
火车脱轨的消息
of derailed trains,
车厢起火了
of granaries on fire,
第五区的水电站遭到了攻击
and of a savage attack on the hydroelectric dam in District 5.
他们对你做了什么
Oh, what have they done to you?
我呼吁大家约束自己的行为
I'm begging for restraint and decency.
我切断了他们的广播
We interrupt your regularly scheduled horse manure
插入你的
to bring you...
就是这个 这是我们的录像带
That's it. That's our footage.
比特黑了进去
Beetee's in.
凯特尼斯
Katniss?
他看见了 他看见我们的短片了
He sees it. He sees our propo.
凯特尼斯 是你吗
Katniss, are you there?
皮塔
Peeta.
凯特尼斯
Katniss?
皮塔 请继续说
Peeta, please continue.
你正在跟我们说
You were telling us about
这些残暴的攻击
these savage attacks.
是的
Yeah.
攻击水电站是一个残酷的
The attack on the dam was a callous
毫无人性的破坏行为
and inhuman act of destruction...
好好想想吧
Think about it.
这一切将如何结束 还将剩下什么
How will this end? What will be left?
没有人能从中幸存
No one can survive this.
现在没有人是安全的
No one is safe now.
凯匹特不安全
Not here in the Capitol.
任何一个区都不安全
Not in any of the districts.
他们来了 凯特尼斯
They're coming, Katniss.
他们要杀死所有人
They're gonna kill everyone.
明天天亮之前你们都将死在13区
And in District 13 you'll be dead by morning.
他在警告我们 这是一个警告
He's warning us. That was a warning.
是的 是一个警告
Yes, it was.
我们得在他们杀了他之前 把他救出来
We have to get him out before they kill him.
空中有什么情况吗
Is there anything in the air?
雷达没有响应 女士
Nothing on Doppler, ma'am.
他在大厦里面 他一定是听到了些机密
He was in the mansion. He could have overheard something.
也许吧
Possibly.
是时候发动空袭演习了
It's time for an air raid drill.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静
Please, remain calm
有序撤离到指定安全区域
and begin evacuation protocol.
波丽姆 波丽姆
Prim! Prim!
请进入离你最近的楼梯井
Proceed to your nearest stairwell
下降到地下40层
and descend to level 40.
防爆门将在六分钟内被封死
Blast doors will be sealed in six minutes.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静
Please, remain calm
有序撤离到指定安全区域
and begin evacuation protocol.
请进入离你最近的楼梯井
Proceed in an orderly fashion to your nearest stairwell
并下降到地下40层
and descend to level 40.
总统女士
Madam President,
三支凯匹特的空中军队刚刚进入到我们的空中领域
three Capitol squadrons just entered our airspace.
我们还有多少时间
How much time do we have?
还有几秒钟就进入射击范围
They're a few seconds from range.
准备紧急起飞舰队
Prepare to scramble the fleet.
收到
Copy that.
打开近距离空中防御导弹系统
Open up short-range air defense.
准备发射长焦距反袭击导弹
Arm long-range missiles for counterattack.
防爆门将在五分钟后关闭
Blast doors will be sealed in five minutes.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静
Please, remain calm
有序撤离到指定安全区域
and begin evacuation protocol.
请进入离你
Proceed in an orderly fashion
最近的楼梯井
to your nearest stairwell
并下降到40层
and descend to level 40.
防爆门将在四分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in four minutes.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静
Please, remain calm
有序撤离到指定安全区域
and begin evacuation protocol.
请进入离你
Proceed in an orderly fashion
最近的楼梯井
to your nearest stairwell
并下降到40层
and descend to level 40.
防爆门将在三分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in three minutes.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
请进入离你
Proceed in an orderly fashion
最近的楼梯井
to your nearest stairwell
并下降到40层
and descend to level 40.
请每个人前往仓库为你所在部门的所有成员
Continue to the Supply Station and claim one pack
获取指定发放物品
for each member of your compartment.
请将个人物品放在指定区域
Please keep all personal items within your assigned area.
礼让每一位市民
Be courteous to your fellow citizens.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
所有市民都应该进入到地堡里
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
防爆门将在两分钟后关闭 妈
Blast doors will close in two minutes. Mom!
波丽姆在哪里
Where's Prim?
我以为她去找你了
I thought she went to find you.
她一定还在楼梯上
She must still be on the stairs.
楼梯上没人
There's no one on the stairs.
她回去找她的猫了
She went back for the cat.
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
所有市民都得进入到地堡
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
嘿 停下 停下
Hey, stop! Stop!
防爆门将在一分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in one minute.
他们轰炸了西北区域的终端
They hit the far edge of the northwest quadrant.
威力渗入地表下四十英尺
Penetrated 40 feet.
没有击中生存区
Missed the living quarters.
现在只有二号和三号走廊有微小的损坏
Only minor damage to corridors 2 and 3.
有监测到辐射吗
Is there any radiation?
暂时没有侦测到
None detected.
雷达显示第四波攻击正在靠近
Doppler shows a fourth wave approaching.
防爆门将在三十秒内关闭
Blast doors will close in 30 seconds.
波丽姆
Prim!
凯特尼斯
Katniss!
发布红色警戒
This is a code red alert.
凯特尼斯
Katniss!
防爆门将在十五秒后关闭
Blast doors will close in 15 seconds.
快下来
Get down here!
快 发布红色警戒
Hurry! This is a code red alert.
防爆门将在十秒后关闭
Blast doors will close in 10 seconds.
九
Nine...
八
Eight...
七
Seven...
六
Six...
-五 -别关门
- Five... - Hold the doors!
四
Four...
三
Three...
二 等等 别关门
Two... Wait! Hold the doors!
一
One.
你为一只猫跑回去 你到底在想什么
You went back for the cat? What were you thinking?
我不会把它丢在那里的
I wasn't gonna leave him behind.
我一个人怎么活
I couldn't live with myself.
防爆门已关闭
Blast doors are now sealed.
我懂 波丽姆
I know, Prim.
走吧
Let's go.
西北方蓄水层遭到攻击
Damage to the aquifer in the northwest quadrant.
我们损失了一个运输通道
We lost a transport corridor.
西北方什么都没有了
There's nothing else in the northwest.
我们在三区的反空袭机枪
Our surface-to-air launchers just took
被直接命中
a direct hit in sector 3.
我们暴露了自己
Because we revealed ourselves.
他们看到我们在那里开火
They saw us firing there.
停止攻击 取消派遣舰队
Stand down. Don't launch the fleet.
另外十二架凯匹特轰炸机
Another 12 Capitol bombers
以轰炸队形逼近三区
approaching sector 3 in attack formation.
等他们靠近了再开火
Hold fire on their approach.
哦
Oh.
他们击中了什么
What'd they hit?
基岩 岩石碎片弹到了通风井里
Bedrock. But there's debris in the ventilation shaft.
他们并没有瞄准我们的舰队
They're not targeting our fleet.
也没有瞄准我们的特制武器
Or our Special Weaponry.
他们不知道我们有什么 也不知道我们的东西在哪里
They don't know what we have or where we have it.
你能保证地堡内全员幸存吗
Can you confirm that everyone's safely in the bunker?
已经确认了
Already done.
把剩下的高射炮都隐藏起来
Conceal all remaining anti-aircraft guns.
关闭发射台和通风走廊
Seal launching pads and ventilation corridors.
我们等着这次轰炸结束
We are gonna wait this out.
建造地堡目的就在于此
This is what we're built for.
他们会把我们封死在这里的
They'll seal us in here like a tomb.
凯匹特掌握的信息已经过时了
The Capitol's working off some outdated information.
我可不想为他们更新信息
I'd rather not update it for them.
总统女士 我知道这事轮不到我管
Madam President, I know it's not my place...
确实轮不到 我们欢迎你来作指导
It's not. You're a welcome guest,
但这事并不属于你的范畴
but you're out of your depth down here.
降低氧气至百分之十四点用于储存
Reduce oxygen to 14% to conserve it.
收到
Copy that.
深呼吸 海文斯贝先生
Take a deep breath, Mr. Heavensbee.
这将是一个漫长的夜晚
It's gonna be a long night.
波丽姆 随便说点什么吧
Prim, talk about something. Anything.
他们把我提拔到了医院
They promoted me at the hospital.
我忘了告诉你了
I forgot to tell you.
他们正在培养我成为一名医生
They're training me to be a doctor.
他们不这么做就是傻瓜
They'd be stupid not to.
嘿
Hey.
我可以坐下吗
Can I sit?
当然可以
Yeah.
斯诺利用安妮来惩罚你
Snow's using Annie to punish you.
他用他们来嘲弄我们
He's taunting us with them.
直到看着这只蠢猫玩耍
I didn't understand until just now
我才明白
watching that stupid cat.
在你参加的第一场游戏之后
After your first Games,
我以为这整个爱情故事就只是演戏
I thought the whole romance was an act.
我们都希望你能继续这个战略
We all expected you to continue that strategy.
但事实并非如此 直到皮塔心脏停止跳动
But it wasn't until Peeta's heart stopped
快要死去的时候
and he nearly died that
我知道我误会你了
I knew I'd misjudged you.
你爱他
You love him.
我没有别的意思
I'm not saying in what way.
可能你甚至都不了解你自己
Maybe you don't even know yourself.
但所有人都注意到了
But anyone paying attention can see it.
你是怎么承受得住的
How do you live with it?
我脱离了噩梦
I drag myself outta nightmares
却在醒来后找不到任何信念
and there's no relief in waking up.
但这也好过放弃
But it's better not to give in to it.
比起毁于一旦 你需要花十倍的努力才能
Takes 10 times longer to put yourself back together
重新振作起来
than it does to fall apart.
凯特尼斯 凯特尼斯
Katniss? Katniss?
跟我来
Come with me.
我们已经承受住了他们最猛烈的攻击了 是吧
We took their best shot. Didn't we?
是的
Yeah.
你妈妈和妹妹没事吧
Your mother and sister okay?
他们没事
Yeah, they're fine.
我需要你替我们办点事情
I need you to do something for us.
我需要你去告诉帕纳姆国
I need you to tell Panem
我们在凯匹特的袭击中活了下来
that we survived an attack by the Capitol
没有人员伤亡
with no casualties.
我们依然在正常的运作
And we remain fully operational.
好的
Okay.
有些事你必须知道
You should know something.
因为皮塔的警告
We had eight extra minutes of civilian evacuation
我们多了八分钟的撤离时间
because of Peeta's warning.
我不会忘记这一点的
I won't forget that.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以 凯特尼斯
So Katniss,
一会你要说 十三区的人们还活得好好的 我也一样
it's "13 is alive and well and so am I."
凯特尼斯
Katniss?
Katniss.
永远是那个浪费彩排机会的人 我就知道
Never one to waste it in rehearsal, I know.
他们为什么要投下这个
Why would they drop these?
为了我
For me.
准备好了吗 凯特尼斯
Ready to go, Katniss?
我们能做到的 就像在第八区一样
We're gonna do this, just like District 8.
和我讲讲玫瑰的事
Tell me about the roses.
告诉斯诺 十三区的还活得好好的
Tell Snow 13 is alive and well.
他会杀了皮塔的
He's gonna kill Peeta.
再来一遍 你能说大声点吗
Let's try again. Can you speak up?
你身上没有麦克风
We don't have a mic on you.
十三区的人们还活得好好的 我也一样
"13 is alive and well and so am I."
他会杀了皮塔的
He's gonna kill Peeta.
我做不到
I can't.
凯特尼斯
Katniss?
你可以的 凯特尼斯
You can do it, Katniss.
我做不到
I can't do this.
十三区的人们还活得好好的 我也一样
"13 is alive and well and so am I."
他还会继续的
He's just gonna keep...
他不会善罢甘休的
He's never gonna stop.
克雷西达 我们得关掉摄像机
Cressida, we should cut the cameras.
只要我还是嘲笑鸟一天 没事的 凯特尼斯
...as long as I'm The Mockingjay. It's okay, Katniss.
不 他警告过我的 他警告过我的
No. He warned me. He warned me about this.
他会这么做是因为我是嘲笑鸟
He's doing this because I'm The Mockingjay.
他惩罚皮塔来惩罚我
He's punishing Peeta to punish me.
不
No.
不 我做不到
No, I can't do this.
凯特尼斯
Katniss.
别逼我做这个
Don't make me do this!
让她走
Let her go.
我要离开这里
I gotta get out of here.
这里就是最底层 是吗
So this is the end, huh?
我猜你是要在这下面躲一辈子
I s'pose you're just gonna hide down here forever?
我不能做嘲笑鸟
I can't be The Mockingjay.
你不是嘲笑鸟 做你自己就好
Not The Mockingjay. Just Katniss.
你知道的 你是我在这下面
You know, you're the only
唯一的朋友
real friend I have down here.
我想他们
I don't suppose they gave you
没有给你一些药物吧
any kind of medication?
你太过分了
You're unbelievable.
好吧 不过我是认真的
Okay, but I meant what I said.
我来这里是为了告诉你
Look, the reason I'm here is to let you know
他们正要去救皮塔
they're rescuing Peeta.
什么
What?
第五区被摧毁的水电站
The dam went down in District 5,
切断了凯匹特大部分的电力
took out most of the power to the Capitol.
毁了他们的防御警报
Knocked out their signal defense.
比特已经黑进了他们的系统
Beetee's inside their system now,
正在做各种破坏
wreaking all kinds of havoc.
替我们打开了一扇窗口
A window is open to us.
能持续多久 我不知道
How much longer? I don't know.
不过我想 应该是到凯匹特
I guess until the Capitol
恢复电力为止
can get the power back on.
科因总统呢
And President Coin?
你知道的 根据他们在这地下的所作所为
You know, I can never fully support that woman
我是不会全心全意
in light of the prohibition
支持这个女人的
they have going on around this place,
但普鲁塔什收到了消息说
but Plutarch got word
皮塔和其他人被关在贡品中心
that Peeta and the others are in the Tribute Center.
一旦电力被切断
And with the power out,
科因一定会抓住这个机会
Coin sees this as an opportunity.
她知道皮塔
She knows that Peeta
是凯匹特的武器 就如同你是我们的武器一样
is the Capitol's weapon. The same way you're ours.
与其让你们两
And as opposed to having you two
彼此敌对
pointing at each other,
她宁愿去救他
she's going to get him.
我得去帮忙
I have to go help.
嘿 嘿 哇哦 孩子 等等
Hey, hey, whoa, kiddo. Wait.
别逗了 怎么 难道你想从通风口跳出去
Come on. What, are you just gonna jump outta the vent
乘着风暴潜进凯匹特吗
and go storm the Capitol?
再说了 行动已经在进行了
Besides, it's already underway.
六名士兵参加行动 全都是自愿的
Six soldiers went in. Volunteer only.
猜猜谁是第一个报名的
And guess who was the first brave soul to sign up.
盖尔
Gale.
准备好了吗 芬尼克  准备好了
Okay, Finnick? Yeah. Yeah.
去中间站着 岩石那儿
Go in the center there. Those rocks.
凯斯特 去左边
Castor, to left.
波力克斯 你待在我这儿
Pollux, you're with me.
我们直接开拍了
So we'll go straight to camera.
好了吗 芬尼克
Okay? Finnick?
好了
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
放松 慢慢说
Take your time.
记住要连续说话 不要停
Just remember to keep talking and don't stop.
我是第65届饥饿游戏的冠军
Winner of the 65th Hunger Games.
我现在正从13区向你发送视频 我活得好好的
And I'm coming to you from District 13, alive and well.
我们在凯匹特的袭击中幸存下来
We've survived an assault from the Capitol.
但我在这里不是来向你们汇报最新消息的
But I'm not here to give you recent news.
为什么是芬尼克去录短片
Why is Finnick doing a propo?
这事说来话长
It's a lot more than that.
比特占住系统了
Beetee's commandeered the system.
现在正在入侵发电机
Now that they're down to generator power
能够入侵的有效频率范围有限
there's a more limited range of frequencies available to them.
我正在用芬尼克的短片替换全部频率
And I'm filling them all up with Finnick.
不会有很多人看到 但不论是谁看到
Not many will see it, but whoever does
都会以为这只是另一段短片
will think it's another propo.
他们不知道的是 这个广播已经
What they don't know is this broadcast
干扰了他们整个系统了
is jamming their entire system with noise.
预警防御系统 内部通讯 所有的一切
Early defense warning, internal communications, everything.
只要广播还在播放
As long as the broadcast goes through,
我们的队伍就能神不知鬼不觉的进出
our team should be able to get in and out undetected.
是真相 而不是奢华生活的神话
The truth. Not the myths about a life of luxury.
不是为你家园光宗耀祖的谎言
Not the lie about glory for your homeland.
你能在竞技中生存下来
You can survive the arena.
只要你脱离游戏 你就会成为一个奴隶
The moment you leave, you're a slave.
嘲笑鸟一号 嘲笑鸟一号
Mockingjay One, Mockingjay One,
一分钟内到达外围防御封锁线
you are one minute out from perimeter defense.
关灯
Going dark.
斯诺总统之前也曾把我当奴隶来卖
President Snow used to sell me.
至少是卖了我的身体 但我不是唯一的一个
Or my body, at least. I wasn't the only one.
如果有哪个胜利者招人喜欢
If a Victor is considered desirable,
斯诺总统就会把他们当做一份奖励送人
the President gives them
或者允许某些人出钱把他们买下来
as a reward or allows people to buy them.
如果你拒绝 他就杀死你爱的人
If you refuse, he kills someone you love.
嘲笑鸟一号 还有二十秒钟突破外围防御
Mockingjay One, you are 20 seconds from perimeter defense.
十秒
Ten seconds.
九 八
Nine... Eight...
七 六 五
Seven... Six... Five...
四 三 二
Four... Three... Two...
一
One.
外围防御无反应
No response from perimeter defense.
我们现在在凯匹特的领空
We're inside Capitol airspace.
为了让他们自己好受些
To make themselves feel better,
我的赞助人常常给我父母送金钱或者珠宝
my patrons would make presents of money or jewelry.
但我发现了比他们给的更有价值的东西
But I found a much more valuable form of payment.
那就是秘密
Secrets.
做好准备
Gear up.
转换为夜间模式
Switching to Night View.
那里
There.
总部 我们看到贡品中心 了
Command, we have visual on the Tribute Center.
准备着陆
Initiating final approach.
戴上面具
Masks on.
我知道凯匹特高级精英阶层的
See, I know all the depravity,
堕落 欺骗 残暴
the deceit and the cruelty
的一切真相
of the Capitol's pampered elite.
但最大的秘密是关于
But the biggest secrets are about
我们的好总统 科里奥兰纳斯·斯诺
our good President, Coriolanus Snow.
开舱门
Open the door.
指挥部 这里是队长
Command, this is Team Leader.
准备释放毒气 进入内部后确认
Prepare to deploy gas. We will confirm once inside.
如此年轻时就爬到权力顶峰
Such a young man when he rose to power.
如此聪明能够保持自己的权力
Such a clever one to keep it.
你一定会问 他是怎么做到的
How, you may ask, did he do it?
两个字
One word.
毒药
Poison.
准备降落
Get ready to drop.
他把一切暴乱都扼杀在摇篮里
He stopped every mutiny before it even started.
安全
Clear.
安全 指挥部 我们已进入
Clear. Command, we're inside.
现在前往第一目标
Heading toward target number one.
P45牢房 C区二楼
Cell P45 lower level 2C.
有毒气
Gas.
他的敌人都会莫名其妙
There are so many mysterious deaths
的死亡
to adversaries.
即使你是盟友 也同样是威胁
Even to allies who were threats.
斯诺本人也用放了毒药的杯子饮酒
Snow would drink from the same cup,
来消除人们的疑虑
to deflect suspicion.
但解毒剂并不总能起作用
But antidotes don't always work,
这就是为什么他总是用玫瑰花味道的香水
which is why he wears roses that reek of perfume.
以遮掩他嘴里永不会痊愈的
Help cover the scent of blood from sores
烂疮的血腥味
in his mouth that will never heal.
盖尔
Gale.
但他却无法遮掩他骨子里的恶臭
But he can't hide the scent of who he really is.
他是无情的侩子手
He kills without mercy.
用欺骗和恐吓手段统治着人们
He rules with deception and fear.
这就是
His weapon of choice
他唯一会使用的武器
is the only thing suited to such a man.
毒药
Poison.
对于狡猾的人来说最完美的武器
The perfect weapon for a snake.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
比特 我和他们失联了
Beetee? I'm losing them.
重新启动
Powering back up.
总统女士 凯匹特的空中防御系统
Ma'am, the Capitol air defense system
正在重启 已经恢复连线
is rebooting. It's coming back online.
他们一定是连接上了另个一电力系统
Must be diverting power from another source.
马上就会中断连接
And filtering transmissions.
再有六十秒 我们的信号就会被阻断
Another 60 seconds and we'll be cut off.
总统女士 我们要召回战斗机吗
Madam President, should we call back the hovercraft?
播放我的画面
Broadcast me.
如果斯诺正在看 如果他看见我的话
If Snow's watching this, maybe he'll let the signal in,
或许他就不会阻断信号
if he sees me.
直播我的画面 他就能看见了
Put me on the air so he can see me.
没错 没错
Yes. Yes.
直播她
Put her on.
能行吗 我们能接入信号吗
Can we do this? Can we still get in?
暂时还可以
Yes. For the moment.
线路通畅 他只能看见你
The line's open. He will only see you.
好了 凯特尼斯 开始
Okay, Katniss, go.
斯诺总统
President Snow?
斯诺总统 我是凯特尼斯
President Snow. It's Katniss.
又不能保证他一定在看
There's no guarantee he's even watching.
我知道 但至少有一线希望
I know, but he might be.
斯诺总统 我有话要对你说
President Snow, I need to speak with you.
你在看吗
Are you there?
斯诺总统 我是凯特尼斯 你能听见吗
President Snow, it's Katniss. Can you hear me?
我有话要对你说
I need to speak with you.
斯诺总统 我是凯特尼斯
President Snow, it's Katniss.
斯诺总统
President Snow,
你在听吗
are you there?
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
斯诺总统
President Snow...
-伊夫狄恩小姐 -真荣幸啊
- Miss Everdeen. - What an honor.
我不敢相信你为了我送你的玫瑰
I don't imagine you're calling
特意致电给我
to thank me for the roses.
这从不是我想要的
I never asked for this.
我从没有要求加入饥饿游戏
I never asked to be in the Games.
博格斯 收到回复 博格斯
Boggs? Come in. Boggs?
我也从没要求成为嘲笑鸟
I never asked to be The Mockingjay.
我只是为了救我妹妹
Just wanted to save my sister.
让皮塔活下去
And keep Peeta alive.
收到请回复 博格斯
Come in. Boggs?
请放了他吧
Please, just let him go.
我不会再当嘲笑鸟
And I will stop being The Mockingjay.
我会消失 你永远都不会再见到我
I will disappear. You will never have to see me ever again.
伊夫狄恩小姐
Miss Everdeen.
博格斯 收到请回复
Boggs, come in.
比起你从游戏里逃脱而言
You couldn't run from this...
收到
Copy.
你是无法继续逃避这一切的
...any more than you could have run from the Games.
指挥部 请说明情况
Command, I need a situation report.
博格斯 时间不多了 要迅速
Boggs, we're running out of time. Hurry.
行动
Let's move.
求你了
Please.
你已经赢了
You've won.
你已经打败我了
You've already beaten me.
放了皮塔 我来代替他
Release Peeta. And take me instead.
自我牺牲的机会
We're long past the opportunity
早就过去了
for noble sacrifice.
那就告诉我该怎么做
Then tell me what to do.
我一直言而有信 不是吗
I've always kept my promises, haven't I?
你说过你不想要战争
You said you didn't want a war.
但是不久之前就发生了
And that's just what's happened.
我告诉过你 和平是多么的脆弱
I told you what a fragile thing peace was.
你却还像个孩子一样
And still, like a child,
高高兴兴的去破坏这一切
you took pleasure in breaking it.
我知道你是哪类人
I know what you are.
我知道你被自己狭隘的想法限制了
I know you can't see past your narrowest concerns.
算了吧 伊夫狄恩小姐
But please, Miss Everdeen.
我甚至开始怀疑你还知不知道诚实是什么了
I doubt you know what honesty is anymore.
指挥部 我们已到达第一目标
Command, we're at the first target.
准备拯救皮塔
Preparing to extract Peeta.
见到他后再向你们确认
Will confirm when he's in hand.
嘲笑鸟一号 战斗机已准备好撤离
Mockingjay One, prepare hovercraft for evac.
你曾要求我说服你
You asked me to convince you
我深爱着皮塔
that I was in love with Peeta.
至少我做到了吧
Haven't I at least done that?
伊夫狄恩小姐
Miss Everdeen,
最爱的人
it's the things we love most
往往伤我们最深
that destroy us.
我希望你记住我这句话
I want you to remember that I said that.
防御解除
你难道以为我不知道
Don't you think I know
你的朋友们在贡品中心吗
your friends are in the Tribute Center?
切断信号
Cut them off.
-发生什么事了 -博格斯 回复
- What happened? - Boggs, come in.
发生什么事了
What happened?
博格斯 收到了吗
Boggs, come in. Do you read me?
他知道他们在里面
He knows that they're in there.
-是个陷阱  -凯特尼斯 冷静点
-It's a trap.  -Katniss, hold it.
我们必须联系上他们
We have to get a hold of them.
我们必须告诉他们快点撤离 他知道了
We have to tell them to get out. He knows.
已经失去信号了 我们联系不上他们
There's no signal. We can't contact them.
不 黑密曲
No. Haymitch,
他从一开始就知道 他在嘲弄我
he knew the whole time. He was taunting me.
-不 黑密曲 他们还在里面  -我们并不确定
-No, Haymitch. They're in there. -No, we don't know that.
我又失去了他们吗
Did I lose them both tonight?
-我又失去了他们吗   -嘘
-Did I lose them both tonight?   -Shh.
我失去他们了吗 我失去他们了
Did I lose them? I lost them both.
不 不
No! No!
还没有进一步的消息
There's no news.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这是世界上最残酷的折磨
It's the worst torture in the world.
等待 明知道自己什么都做不了
Waiting, when you know there's nothing you can do.
尤其是像我们这样的人
Especially for people like us.
但无论是力量 勇气
But whatever strength, courage,
还是愤怒
madness,
是我们走下去的动力 你会在这种时候
keeps us going, you find it,
找到这种感觉的
at times like these.
你有这个能力 战士
You have it, soldier.
这就是这么久以来你得以保命的原因
It's what's kept you alive all this time.
这是不会让你倒下的
And it won't fail you now.
他们回来了
They're back.
我不要这个
I don't want that.
乔安娜
Johanna.
芬尼克
Finnick!
安妮 安妮
Annie? Annie!
你没事 太好了
You're safe. You're safe.
盖尔
Gale!
你还好吗
Are you okay?
怎么了 什么事
What? What is it?
我想不明白
I don't get it.
他们所有的武器都已上膛
Every gun was back online
对准了我们 而我们就那样飞了过去
and on us and we flew right past them.
他们故意放走我们的
They let us go.
他就在那儿
He's in there.
我们用来迷晕警卫的毒气
Gas we used on the guards
也波及到他了 但已经慢慢缓过来了
knocked him out, too, but it's wearing off now.
你应该在他醒来的时候守在旁边
You should be there when he wakes up.
谢谢你
Thank you.
皮塔
Peeta.
Peeta!
皮塔 放手 放开她
Peeta! Get off! Get off of her!
放手
Let go!
不 凯特尼斯 不 你颈部肿了 别碰它
No, Katniss. No, you're swollen. Don't touch.
不 不 不 冷静
No, no, no. Calm down.
冷静 你没事
Calm down. You're okay.
告诉总统女士 她醒了
Tell her she's awake.
先别说话
Don't try to talk.
皮塔没事 我保证
Peeta's okay. I promise.
我只是为了让他放开你
I just had to get him off you.
这叫做意念操纵
It's called hijacking.
我们不知道凯匹特究竟这样折磨皮塔了多久
We don't know how long the Capitol's been doing this to Peeta.
这是对恐惧的条件反射
It's fear conditioning.
被杀人蜂的毒液扩大了感知
Enhanced with tracker jacker venom.
你第一次参赛的时候被蛰了 记得吗
You were stung your first Games. Remember?
毒液让宿主处于游离状态
The venom puts the subject in a dissociative state.
他们就在这时折磨他
And they torture him.
利用电击和殴打 摧残他的本性
With shocks and beatings, and strip down his identity.
然后把所有的痛苦和恐惧重新定向
And then all of that suffering and fear is redirected.
与其他记忆或人关联起来
Associated with other memories or a person.
他们能改变他对凯特尼斯的记忆
They can change his memories of Katniss?
让她变成对他生命有威胁的人
To make her seem life-threatening.
他们把他变成了武器 凯特尼斯
They turned him into a weapon, Katniss.
来杀你
To kill you.
你们能治好他的 对吧
But you can reverse it?
恐惧是最难克服的东西
The fear is the most difficult thing to overcome.
我们本能地会把恐惧记得最深
We're hardwired to remember fear best.
这是个新的领域
It's new terrain.
但我们已经召集了一个团队
But we've put together a team.
还是很乐观的
I'm optimistic.
晚上好
Good evening.
昨天 我授权了
Yesterday, I authorized
一个潜入凯匹特的秘密行动
a covert rescue mission inside the Capitol.
我非常高兴的宣布
I am pleased to announce
胜利者们已全数救出
that the Victors have been liberated!
让今天成为历史性的一天
Let this day mark an historic change.
拥有嘲笑鸟和胜利者们与我们并肩作战
With The Mockingjay and the Victors beside us,
我们已明确地向凯匹特发出了讯息
we have sent a clear message to the Capitol.
我们再也不会忍辱吞声了
That we will never again endure injustice.
今天
Today,
是我们与家人
a day on which we reunited family,
朋友 爱人团聚的日子
friends, and loved ones.
让我们帕纳姆国团结一心
Let all of Panem come together.
不为寻求报复凯匹特的快感
Not to battle for the amusement of the Capitol.
只为共同战斗
But to join hands in this fight.
让今天成为我们承诺
Let today be the day we promise
永不放弃 永不屈服
never to give up, never to give in
直到新帕纳姆国成立
until we have made a new Panem,
民主选举领导人 没有压迫的一天
where leaders are elected, not imposed upon us.
成为各区自由共享
And where the districts are free
劳动果实
to share the fruits of their labors
再也不为残羹冷炙争抢的一天
and not fight one another for scraps!
新帕纳姆国已近在眼前
This new Panem is on the horizon.
但我们必须自己争取
But we must take it for ourselves.
通往第2区的是峥嵘山势
The road there leads through the sharp mountains
和深沟险壑
and deep ravines of District 2.
那里是
There in the heart
帕纳姆最为险峻的所在
of Panem's steepest mountain range lies
那里有凯匹特重要的军事基地
the Capitol's principal military facility.
我们能够征服这座要塞
We can conquer this stronghold
因为我们是同一个人
because we are one people,
同一支军队 同一种声音
one army, one voice.
因为今天就是我们新的起点
Because today is our new beginning.
今天我们解放了胜利者们
Today we have freed the Victors.
明天我们将解放帕纳姆
Tomorrow, Panem!
万岁 万岁 万岁
Hoorah! Hoorah! Hoorah!